JACQUES PILLET

jacquespillet5@gmail.com http://jacquespillet.github.io

Software Engineer based in Marseille, France, with 8 years of full-time experience in software development, specializing in computer graphics.

Currently working at ScanLAB Projects, an award-winning creative studio in London.

Open to new opportunities in computer graphics and software development.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Lead Software Engineer

2018 - Present

2017 - 2018

ScanLAB Projects

London, UK / Marseille, France

- · Development of the in-house offline rendering engine, used across all projects for creating films.
- · Development XR experiences with Unity using custom rendering pipelines.
- · Creation of technical infrastructures for screen-based immersive installations.
- · Design of new architectures for capturing and processing point cloud data.
- · Continuous integration of cutting-edge point-based graphics research to keep our technology at the forefront of the industry.
- · Key Projects:
 - FRAMERATE (Tribeca Film Festival, Biennale di Venezia, SXSW, BFI...) : Development of the rendering technology and asset management pipeline
 - *Eternal Return* (SXSW, CPH:DOX), *Buried in the rock* (IDFA, Belfast XR) : Creation of XR Experiences for various headsets (Oculus Quest, Rift, HTC Vive)
 - Adult Children (Donmar Warehouse, BFI, Luxembourg Film Festival), Felix's Room (Berliner Ensemble), Pistol by Danny Boyle (FX, HULU, Disney+): Real time point cloud capture, processing and rendering tools
 - Variants by Pierre Huyghe (Kistefos Museum, Norway) : Development of the real-time rendering pipeline for the outdoor screen of the installation
 - Explore Soane Museum website (The Sir John Soane Museum): Development of all the 3D parts of the website

Software Engineer

Freelance Paris, France

- \cdot collaboration with my university for creating Blizaar, a 2.5D visualization of a multilayer graph in the web browser.
- · Creation of an augmented reality mobile application for a museum with Unity (Proof of concept for a consulting firm)
- · Creation of a mobile app for Epilepsie France, as the lead developper in a team of 3 people.

Software EngineerModis France
2016 - 2017
Paris, France

- · Development of mobile applications (Java, Apache Cordova), mainly back office for big companies
- · Development of website back ends (PHP Symfony) and front ends (Angular), mainly back office for big companies

EDUCATION

CY Cergy Paris Université

MSc in Mathematics and Computer Science

2013 - 2016 Cergy, France

Grenoble Ecole de Management

MSc in Management

 $2013 - 2016 \\ Grenoble, \ France$

SKILLS

• Programming: C, C++, Python, Java.

• Tech: Computer Graphics Techniques and Algorithms, OpenGL, Vulkan, Direct3D11/12, Cuda.

• Languages: English, French.

PROJECTS

• Personnal Website: jacquespillet.github.io

• Blog: jacquespillet.blogspot.com/

• Github: https://github.com/jacquespillet